

Lensa A.

.NET Developer

### General info

Work experience Location

10+ years total Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Time zone: UTC+3

## Top technologies

.NET	5+ years experience	1 2 3 4 5+
.NET Core	5+ years experience	12345+
C#	5+ years experience	12345+
ASP .NET	5+ years experience	12345+
JavaScript	4 years experience	1 2 3 4 5+

# **Technologies**



### Bio

### Main areas of expertise

Full-stack web development.

#### ### Main tech stack

I am an experienced .NET developer who had worked with different companies over the years. My specialty is mainly .NET with C# as the main programming language. Used the following technologies in past projects:

- JavaScript:> Over 4 years of professional experience
- .NET:> Over 5 years of professional experience
- ASP.NET:> Over 5 years of professional experience
- C#:> Over 5 years of professional experience
- SQL:>Over 5 years of professional experience

I'm interested in Senior developer jobs, where I work with my main technologies.

### Experience

Senior Technical Consultant

01/2018 - 03/2022

Fairfax Technologies (Ethiopia/Addis Ababa)

4 years and 2 months

During this period I worked as Senior Oracle Apps Technical Consultant. The project is an Oracle EBS Application, an ERP technology, is an Oracle Application Implementation for Development

Bank of Ethiopia (DBE) with a budget of 1.6 million USD.

The project is implemented for over 1000 branch offices. I was mainly involved in the technical support of the different financial modules which are developing new forms and reports, customizations upon the client's request, preparation of the different technical documents, development of standalone tools for data migration from legacy systems, customization of the workflows, and designing new for the successful implementation of different business processes.

Senior Technical Consultant

08/2016 - 01/2018

Fairfax Technologies (Ethiopia/Addis Ababa)

1 year and 5 months

EBS Application, an ERP technology, is an Oracle Application Implementation for the Commercial Bank of Ethiopia (CBE) with a budget of 2.7 million USD.

The project is implemented for over 1000 branch offices. I was mainly involved in the technical support of the different financial modules which are developing new forms and reports, customizations upon the client's request, preparation of the different technical documents, developing of standalone tools for data migration from legacy systems, customization of the workflows, and designing new for the successful implementation of different business processes.

**Technical Consultant** 

10/2011 - 11/2016

TCT (Transnational Computer Technology) (Ethiopia/Addis Ababa)

5 years and 1 month

During this period I worked as Senior Oracle Apps Technical Consultant. The project is an Oracle EBS Application, an ERP technology, is an Oracle Application Implementation for the Ministry of

Finance and Economic Development (MOFEC) with budget of 21 million USD. The project is implemented for the six pilot ministries and the two regional offices. I was mainly involved on the technical support of the different financial modules which are developing new forms and reports, customizations upon the client's request, preparation of the different technical documents, development of standalone tools for data migration from legacy systems, customization of the

workflows and designing new for the successful implementation of different business processes.

OracleForms

OracleReports

PL/SQL

Oracle WorkFlow

OracleADF

Team Leader/Application Developer

02/2010 - 10/2011

INSA (Information Network Security Agency) (Ethiopia/Addis Ababa)

1 year and 8 months

I have also worked on another project called Land Tenure and House Management system it is a GIS system that registers the different houses of MoND (Ministry of National Defense) to help it to efficiently manage the houses.

From February 2010 to October 2011. During this period I have worked as a Database Administrator, Application Developer, and also a team leader. This system is a web-based application that enables MOND (Ministry of National Defense) to receive houses, allocate houses, register small-scale maintenance and service expansion and manage service consumption and payment.

| C#

ASP.NET

ADO.NET

SQL

JavaScript

ArcGIS

10/2009 - 10/2010 Application Developer

INSA (Information Network Security Agency) (Ethiopia/Addis Ababa)

1 year

The system developed is a cadaster and real property registration system that includes both the spatial and socio-economic data related to parcels. Oracle server is used to store both the relational database and geo-database i.e. which is responsible for spatial data.

It is implemented using ASP.NET(C# is the programming language). The business logic layer is wrapped in web services. Have participated in the full phase of the application development starting

from the preparation of the Requirement Analysis Document (RAD) up to the end user training. I was in involved in the front end as well as in the data management of the system. Implementing of the application which includes designing the forms, implementing the respective classes in the subsystem and also designing of the database and applying the different oracle concepts to ensure

the security and the availability of the system





ADO.NET



JavaScript

### Education

Bahir Dar University

02/2007 - 12/2009

BSc, Computer Science

2 years and 10 months

### Languages

**English** Fluent